哼。
係。
presentation，可唔可以？
係，唔好嚇我啊！
有冇需要選副主席啊？
係，我哋請政府官員入嚟啦。
阿阿嗯，謝偉謝偉出於。
冇，噉我就交個位畀阿鍾樹根議員啦。
跟住，我哋團長啊，就係委員員啊。
係，就可以嚇，噉就誒。
鍾樹根議員接唔接受？接受。好，有冇其他嘅提名？
誒，我想問下誒各位，想唔想選副主席咧？
如果冇需要咧，噉我哋就誒唔算啦嚇。噉我進入議程，多謝大家嘅支持提名。
提名由一名委員口頭作出，並且最少得到另一名委員口頭附議。嚇，阿李慧瓊議員。你好，我提議阿鍾樹根。係有冇委員獲議？
夠中又夠法定人數，而家我哋係根據西九文化區管理局條例第六零一章第三十七條提出嘅二議決議案小組委員會主席嘅選舉，噉就根據內務守則第二十二條同埋附六四嘅選舉程序咧，而家請委員提名主席一職人選，有效。
你代我。
嚇。
呢個係一個。
OK。
啊。
你看到啦。
同埋誒。
排唔排到隊㗎？
唔好玩我啊，心血少啊嚇！
Obviously, we're here to talk about the public open space bylaws.
Quite a lot's happened in the since the last time we talked, so I thought I'd just bring bring us all up to date, same page, and that'll help us.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman. I'll just take you through this. I thought it would be useful just to set the scene. I know some members are familiar with what's happened before, but
我我同意到，但係排排到隊咧，即係要睇大家誒嘅提問啊，同埋個會議嘅進程。得啊，秘書講講。應該政府當局。
係有關嘅部門或者西九嘅代表會介紹呢個power嘅嚇，噉我哋而家開始先啦嘛，爭取時間。誒，邊位介紹啊？Welcome。
歡迎誒西九管理局同埋誒我哋民政局嘅同事同埋政府同事出席今日嘅會議。咁咧有一個powerpoint咧就派緊畀大家。
撤回咗佢準備三月十六號提出呢個決議案喎。我撤回咗㗎啦，冇日子嘅而家。係冇日子，因為我哋要審完呢個係。審完先啦。明白，明白，明白。先可以再。所以冇呢個問題嘅，我哋慢慢嚟都得嘅，即係。
嗯。
the park.
我。
在 doing so， we。
They are.
by the legislative council in this case through positive vetting.
但 in due course， as the park， which is the area below that， is developed， these will then apply to that area as well。
It's perhaps worth recapping the reason why we're doing the bylaws in the first place, and this is something which I think.
We were requested to put together bylaws to help facilitate the operation of the public open space and the.
Isn't necessarily obvious, but it was in response to the subcommittee on public health and municipal services ordinance bylaws amendments.
Drafted under Section Thirty Seven One of the ordinance, which allows us to to create the bylaws, and of course they all have to be approved.
We're looking at the area, depending on how quickly the bylaws are enacted, which we call the nursery park. Which, if if members have have recollection, this is the area surrounded that rather large circle on the on the diagram.
took regard to the fact that these bylaws will apply throughout the district and not just in the park area, and I think that's important to bear that in mind. So as we gradually develop the area within the district, the bylaws will be rolled out and increasingly apply throughout. But primarily at this stage.
In.
We need to be able to control that.
所以，讓我非常快速地 run us  through the key elements。
The basic objective of the cultural district as a whole.
We need to be able to to step in where necessary to deal with those sort of issues.
primaryly， we believe that the the purpose of the proposed bylaws is to ensure public safety， order and health。
我們 do have to have regard to the environment， and we also have to allow for the smooth conduct of cultural activities within the public open spaces.
which we feel that people should be allowed to do, and we will welcome those. But of course, you do have to control them, and the bylaws provide for suitable controls.
The principles, and I think this is also important. The guiding principle and the philosophy that we're using is that we want the public open space to be as open and as accessible as possible throughout.
所以，concept is that we want to have this open space to inspire, promote and encourage cultural pursuits for all. and I emphasise cultural pursuits here because obviously we wanted to support
In doing so, of course, we do need to have minimum powers to manage the public open space itself, in order to ensure that the open space is available for all on a fair basis and it can be used safely.
在 drafting the bylaws， 我們有引述到本地和海外的法例。我唔係要講到呢個嘅細節， 除咗要證明我哋嘅做法係如何嘅。
looking at this, we've taken a view quite early on in response to public suggestions that we should allow domestic animals. and this basically we mean dogs, cats, that sort of thing. people do bring birds in. we're not talking about alligators and buffalo and that sort of operation. it is something.
minimum restrictions on public conduct. Again, I think this is basically a sensible issue. We don't want to see people causing nuisance or annoyance to other others. They don't want to see damage to the public open space and environment, or we or that may cause danger to to other users. So.
其他key元素， delineation of restricted enclosed areas， and this means things like areas that might need to be closed off for maintenance purposes， areas that might be closed off for back of house operations， storage of mechanical equipment that sort of area， plus of course where
We may have events that need to be controlled. You know, we've had already many many events in the existing nursery park, and we we really understand now how you have to control areas just for safety. If you have three, four, five thousand people in a park, you need to ensure that they can do so safely. So
Okay.
多謝主席。
His legal team.
I'm sure Mr. Pasquod and
approach， and we hope the bylaws as drafted do reflect that approach.
There is only one thing that I want to raise at this moment.
Youth groups, professional institutions, as well as society for the prevention of cruelty to animals.
Where there are breaches of the bylaws, of course, there must be some sort of penalties for contravention, and that is also provided for.
跟住落嚟咧，我哋就進行諮詢。而家有舉咗手咧，就梁家傑、誒蔣麗雲，再冇其他同事舉手。咁首先誒，梁家傑，每人四分鐘，連問連答。
And carried out a public survey on the operation of the future park by the consultation panel. That took place in May and June of two thousand and fourteen.
So that's as far as I want to go at the moment, Mr. Chairman. We're very, very happy to answer members' questions and stand ready to respond. Thank you.
Of course, we need enforcement powers and penalties, and we need to be able to authorise persons with suitable power to enforce the provisions, particularly on types of conduct.
公共 consultation， this was an important part of the both the preparatory process for the drafting of the bylaws as well as the review process as we develop the bylaws. We took it forward on on this basis of a park we share.
We also obviously consulted the Ledgeco Joint Sub Committee, the Yau Tsim Mong District Council. We're in regular dialogue with the Harbourfront Commission, as well as we held a town hall meeting chaired by the Chairman, with all District Councils in attendance. Beyond that.
For specific issues, for example, street performers, youth groups, pets, animals, that sort of thing. We spoke to individual groups and associations, including street performers, particularly the nearby residents. We felt it was important that they had an opportunity to discuss these with us.
One of the key things that came across through this exercise, and it was an extensive exercise over many months, was that there was a strong feeling the bylaws should be minimal, to allow freedom for diverse park users with discretion to be executed flexibly, and we fully subscribe to that.
panel。
That.
of members.
and I emphasise the word objectives.
of the WKCDA joint.
The W K C D A。
must be well versed with the desire.
You will find in subsection two.
Now I understand from the Legislative Council Secretariat.
If you look at Chapter 601 itself.
Under section four, entitled Functions of Authority.
Well, subsection one first that sets out the functions of the authority.
But if I may just clarify with Mr. Pescott and his legal team, why is that so?
For a mission statement to be included in the bylaws.
took the view after consulting lawyers that such a mission statement was not possible.
從A到G，然後在括號二， subsection二，它説，該權威將在subsection一中履行其職能，以達到以下目標。
Chairman。
誒。
Public open spaces itself, etc.
That it is.
the the main legislation in in the ordinance.
係，潘司長。If I could just add,
Okay, principal. I'll start and then I'll ask.
Of Chapter 601, the principal legislation itself. Thank you.
We felt constrained by DOJ's advice.
One of the points that Department of Justice Legal Drafting Division made was that.
There was no need to include the statement in the bylaw, because it was already contained in the in the.
May I inquire why it is the case that you can't adopt a similar formulation in the drafting of the bylaws, so that we can be sure about the objectives of the bylaws, that would include, for example.
It is the objective that the use of public open space should be open, accessible wherever possible. The mission for the public open spaces is to inspire, promote and encourage cultural pursuits for all. Minimum powers for managing the.
Like to chip in. In fact, when we did the first draft, after we did that discussion in the subcommittee, we did prepare a draft with the relevant preamble. When it was submitted to the Department of Justice for vetting, as these things always are, we were advised that it was not the normal protocol in.
terms of this sort of drafting to include it, obviously we're aware of members' strong view on this and felt that in view of that that conflict we would try and deal with it in the guidelines. So that's the approach that we've taken to get the spirit of what members wanted included, but obviously recognising the advice that we'd received from the.
Department of Justice, Mike, do you want to chip in? Yeah, Mr. Chairman, I have limited time. Mr. Peerscourt must be well aware that my question was very focused. I was drawing a comparison between the bylaws that are now being tabled and Section Four.
啊！
嚇噉啊！另外咧，我就想問下咧。
可以考慮嘅小型嘅狗，但係對於大型嘅狗，我係絕對有保留嘅。
Okay, Mr. Chairman. From the attendance list, I do not see.
注意嘅會唔會講清楚咧？就因為咧，你大家講緊家居動物，可能都係仲主要都係狗仔啦。OK，噉就啊呢一樣嘢咧就要講清楚啦，因為咧就嗯。
我係這裡，drawing a comparison to section 4，particularly section 4 bracket 2 of the principal ordinance。OK，好，噉我諗誒書面答覆你啦，嚇下一位就蔣麗雲。
有啲會驚啦，驚有個反應嘅話咧，反而好容易令到嗰啲動物嗰個覺得嚇啊！你會唔會係攻擊我啊？咁嚇，即係而啊，即係香港出現都幾多咧，就係啊小朋友畀啲動啊狗仔咬嘅狗咬。
The Department of Justice being represented today at this Bills Committee, if I may state for the record, so that the secretariat can let the DOJ know that I am not accepting that as a an answer. Perhaps.
On the next occasion when we meet, we can ask the DOJ to be represented. And before that, better still, they can provide us first with a written reply to my query. I hope the secretary already got my point that.
唔該，主席。誒，我係歡迎咧，就係誒，今次嗰個誒公眾優點用地咧，其中個基優氣喺優氣用地咧，其中嘅基本原則咧，就會盡量開放同埋通達啦。咁呢個係好事。咁咧就而我亦都係啊。
歡迎咧，即係當中睇到咧，就係有啲啊啊啊家居嘅動物咧，誒都能夠係啊呢個啊參與呢個休憩用地嘅啊，即係可以去休憩用地。咁不過咧就啊有一點咧，我就希望咧就注。
香港嘅動物同埋啊，即係嗰個誒，有好多家庭係冇養動物嘅。而當啲家庭一家大細咧去到呢一啲啊啊休憩嘅地方度啊行啊，噉你亦都有動物行啊，咁咁咧就有時咧小朋友咧係啊。
所以咧，我就希望咧，大家諗深一層，就係係咪開放所有嘅家居動物咧？咁嗱，而家你知道有啲家居養嗰啲動，有啲狗咧係好大隻嘅嚇，嗰啲叫做咩西藏獒犬嚇嘛嚇，噉佢都係屬於係家居動物，係咪咧？噉啊，應亦都有。
所以那係第一個原則。
咧咁會唔會有啲規範咧咁？因為你唔好唔記得，我哋隔離咧就有好多住宅。
Having said that, it's not just about dogs. We've had all sorts of animals brought in, as I say, birds, and I saw.
ready，which are on our website that we are working with the street performers and we can provide those if if the members interested.
係嘛？咁嗰啲住宅咧，即係一到誒，即係可能會係誒某程度會唔會干擾到人哋咧？咁嗱，呢一樣要要諗清楚，嗯。
and expects of us, but of course within that, certain areas may be controlled access for operational reasons or for hiring reasons. Okay,跟住陳志全議。
must be under the control of their their pet owner or whoever's walking the dogs. Our ambassadors and we've been operating the park now for eight months. Do
啲咧養嗰啲叫大隻嗰啲叫咩單物狗係嘛？嗰啲係好大隻咁呢啲咧就啊呢啲可以咧，即係啊喺某個程度嚟講咧係啊，即係啊可以係對萬一萬一啊，因為人嘅行為或者四周圍嘅行。
行為而令到只狗突然間發狂嘅話咧，係絕對可以嚴重傷害到人生身嘅。咁所以喺呢一度咧，我覺得我哋要考慮多啲。但係我原則上係歡迎細狗狗仔，我覺得可以試行下嘅。我覺得呢樣嘢唔出。
就有關街頭表演者啦。OK，咁呢一度我哋會唔會啊？呢個誒，因為我哋儘量係開放啦。OK，咁個街頭表演者誒喺裏邊個規範如何咧？係咪佢可以去到某一個啊角落位咁噉，佢就可以坐低就可以表演音音樂。
咁咧就另外咧，我亦都想知道咧嗱。噉就啊，我哋個開放時間會唔會考慮咧嚇？即係譬如話，我係咪廿四小時開放嘅啊？定係咧就誒會有一段時間會有啲限制嘅，特別深夜時間嘅噉。咁可唔可以誒喺度即係初步諗法如何咧嚇？
我都想知道下。唔該，Mr Duncan。Thank you. The the point on dogs is actually well taken. We have designated free range area where dogs can be allowed off the leash, but it's separated from the rest of the park, and we expect that to continue. Within the park, the requirement is that dogs
draw this to the attention of the users of the park, and we've not had any problems at all. I'm very pleased to say that. And we've had large dogs and small dogs, because the the emphasis is always on safety. At all times, we want dogs to be under control. That usually means they must be on a leash. They must be able to be reined in at.
hamster or something being brought in by children before it's all sorts of pets but all of them must be under the control of the of the keeper of that particular pet so that point is well taken in terms of street performers Lisa can probably answer in more detail if you need that but there are designated locations within the
And there will be in future within the area. There are restrictions on the type of amplification that people can use, so that they cannot disturb people. There will be restrictions on the duration, so they can't stay in one place for six, seven hours, because of course that can also be very irritating if they're singing one song over.
And over again, so they are required to move on. There are restrictions, for example, on emergency vehicular access areas. They cannot be located in those areas. If an emergency vehicle comes, they must be able to be remove their equipment within two or three minutes. So there are very clear guidelines that are issued and published already.
In terms of potential nuisance to residents, I don't expect that because of the the long distance from the residential areas. It really is a long, long way, so I don't anticipate any problems. The final issue, opening hours. Yes, we intend it to be open 24/7. We feel that that's what the public demand.
Bylaw and we'll discuss those as we go through the bylaw in detail.
security guards， we're using park ambassadors， so we have a low touch。 so instead of saying you cannot do something， we go up and say。
誒可以考慮設置無分性別洗手間，除咗方便跨性別人士，亦都係方便一啲家庭誒一啲誒。
上嘅唔同嘅，但係你話誒逼於無奈，如果冇佢又唔想入男唔想入女，佢逼於無奈會用殘疾人士洗手間，但係。
There are circumstances where you know males need to be accompanied by females if they're blind, if they're not just disabled, they may be.
點樣畀佢哋係嗰個權力管理嘅程度係低咧？至於第三條問題咧，就係關於公廁嘅問題。其實喺誒今次嘅法例裏邊第十六。
least number of regulations to allow us to operate the park and the open space for the benefit of the public. So, for example, we're trying to ensure that, as we already do, that we don't have an approach which requires
多謝主席。誒，首先我想問翻，都係一個程序嘅問題。噉我誒知道政府係即係撤回咗三月十六號要動議呢一個議案啦。噉就等我哋嘅誒委員會處理咗呢條法案。但係大家知道，因為呢條係一個附屬法例啦。咁根據議事規則第十八條咧，佢嘅優先次序咧就會喺法案。
之後嘅咁即係話咧誒，而家因為立法會有好多法案誒累積咗喺度啦。如果咧要做誒附屬法例咧，可能就要再用議事規則，即係再一次用二九十一條去停咗十八條，跟住先至可以先做。我想問下誒秘書長，你有冇時間表？因為我聽緊某啲法有啲非法。
案咧，即係唔係即係唔係唔合法，即係唔係法案咧。佢個優先次序好低，甚至咧會誒有個心力準備會被犧牲嘅。即係如果排唔到噉，我哋呢條有冇一個噉嘅諗法咧？第二個問題咧就係關於其實今日嘅powerpoint都有講，就話呢一個西九嘅呢個誒地方會用最低程。
程度嘅權力管理會係最低程度權力管理嘅公眾休憩用地呢個，我想誒政府或者西九去誒可以解釋多少少。如果呢個講法應該係對比於其他康文署所管轄嘅呢啲叫做誒公眾休憩地方啦，咁西九係。
第六部第十六咧都有講進入公廁嘅問題。我哋喺西九嗰個小組曾經都問過，就係話誒西九文化區會唔會設立無分性別嘅洗手間啊？嗱，我希望官員或者西九嘅誒負責人可以分得清楚無分性別嘅洗手間同誒殘疾人士所用嘅洗手間係有本質上。
實際上邊咧，亦都唔係話為跨性別人士嘅，其實一個家庭友善政策。我曾經真係見過有一個男士一個伯伯噉，佢喺個廁所嗰度咧就摸嚟摸去揾唔到個出口，揾唔到個門啊。噉我我就話啊，點解個失明嘅人士佢唔帶誒嗰個手杖咧？咁原來佢咧係有佢囡囡陪。
陪佢去嗰個地方，但係因為佢女女入唔到去嗰個誒男廁嗰度啦，咁所以喺男廁嗰度佢就即係周圍好似碰碰車噉，周圍撞嚟撞去。噉我就帶佢即係出翻去就見翻佢女女。咁其實而家啲現代或者進步嘅地方，我西九應該嗰個進步嘅地方啦。誒，而家高山劇場啊，陳茂波都走嚟同我講，係我。
我而家有無分性別洗手間啦噉樣咁即係好威咁啦，即係話終於有啦咁好啊。咁西九未來可唔可以有咧？因為而家條法例就五歲以下即係可以進入異性洗手間啦。咁但係大啲，即係個女想帶個老豆入去，就唔知係男廁女廁就一定係犯法㗎啦。咁所以我哋都係好希望。
誒，我哋都係要跟翻嗰個誒議事規則去排隊啦。
而處理咧，你有冇個優先次序咧？你呢條呢條腐例？
and they would be exercising their function under their own powers. They don't need these bylaws.
獲授權人士究竟係咩人？嚇，呢度所謂嘅合理武力係什麼合理武力咯？Okay, Mr. Persico, please. Um, thank you.
Let me make it very, very clear here. We're not talking about armed personnel in any shape or form. The only people who would ever be armed in the park, as far as I'm concerned, are police officers.
又係要叫警察嚟噉係嘛？定抑或係即係你會交畀食環處？定抑或係交畀警察去做咧？邊啲係呢啲獲授權人士咧？同埋喺。
即係呢條附例嘅定第十部嗰度咧都有執行呢度嘅，咁呢個第二十三條嘅執行第括弧五嗰度咧就講明佢需要時係可以使用合理武力。
自己獨立用廁所有困難嘅朋友咯。Okay.誒，Mr. Pascal. Um, I'll I'll deal with the last two. I presume the secretary will deal with the first one. Um, yes, there will be family toilets which will be unisex. I think that's an important point that we learnt from the member's comments previously. Um, I absolutely agree.
mentally disabled, for example, they may need assistance. So we've recognised that there will be those provisions within the park. That's something that we've we've certainly taken advice from members on. In terms of the minimum powers, well, that's what we're trying to set out in the in this bylaw. What we regard as the.
你哋 disturbing your neighbours. Is it possible for you to move a little bit? Is it possible for you to change your behaviour? We're trying that low key approach, and it seems to be working very well so far. We've not had any particular difficulty with that approach in the existing nursery park, so we believe it will work. But the specific provisions, obviously, are in the.
O.K.誒誒，民政局都答埋嗰個上會嗰個時間表。關於嗰個程序問題咧，陳議員講得啱嘅，因為立法會係同意咗成立誒呢一個委員會去審議呢一個附例咧。民政事務局局長係已經係撤回咗啊嗰個誒決議案嗰個動議㗎啦。噉我哋就希望喺呢個委員會度嘅時候，我都可以向委員解釋，亦都多謝委員。
即係對呢個福利嘅關注，我哋嘅時間表咧都係希望可以喺今個立法年度咧都係可以誒完成嘅。咁即係希望，即係我哋喺呢個會度即係講解多啲嘅時候，都希望委員支持我哋呢幾條福利啦。係咪我哋如果譬如完成啦呢個，譬如我哋開幾多次會都完成咗之後，你會會用一個議事程序會確保佢今個年度可以？
噉你哋幫幫手啦。O.K. 唉，問嘅同事問曬在冇同事問啊。啊，唔好意思，睇漏咗你。唔緊要，我都照問嘅，實畀時間問。即係都唔使限時間啦，得兩個。四四分鐘啦，掉下你啦，提醒你。你講咧。噉你唔好，你不如畀我哋即係一個。
對話完完整整啦嚇，你而家繼續啊！議事，我我係想問嗰個誒執行即係執法嗰個機制嘅。其實呢件事咧，就阿陶錦新議員咧，就之前都問過㗎啦。喺西九嗰度咧，即係你西九自己係冇一個武裝部隊㗎嘛嚇。
係嘛係只只係有獲授權人士嘅啫，同埋即係我估你最多都係揾保安公司嚟幫你做嘅。咁但係咧，你前邊就有好多誒誒好多唔準唔準唔準噉。好啦，去到後邊執行嗰度咧就誒。
同埋適宜嗰度咧，都只係話獲授權人士。噉我想問管理局咧，究竟呢批獲授權人士係乜嘢人咧？即係會唔會好似良景村嗰度揾咗啲孔武有力嘅人走嚟趕小販，又叫做保安，又搞到又有即係嗰批人同誒村民有衝突啊？然後又
office。
咁呢個即係請管理局提供資料啊！好嘛，提供資料。Thank you。
我 distinguished by being heavies as you put it.
這些 bye-laws are to allow us to appoint people who are working for us. They will be properly identified.
執行秩序維持秩序嘅時候，即係喺嗰度有個有個基礎畀我哋去去睇得到咯。
the whole concept of this is that while you have bylaws, you have to have the ability to enforce them. But our approach, as I've said before, is to
Times that must be with the minimum necessary force. Now, what what you mean by minimum necessary force will be set out in published guidelines.
At the moment, we have what we call park ambassadors. They wear a uniform. It's very simple, but it's very clearly identified who they are. The powers are very limited. They can, at most, require a person to to accompany them to the park office or a police station. But that is that's at most.
咁嗱，乜嘢叫做合理武力咧？大家真係唔係好明白嘅啫喎，中文英文都即係都要講得非常之清楚。咁如果係合理武力嘅時候，你係咪揾即係外判咗揾個警衞公司，你就畀佢用佢認為嘅合理武力咧？你有冇一啲守則啊、訓練啊、各樣嘢？
同埋即係呢度，你講明後邊第七嗰度咧，就講明呢啲獲授權人士同警隊係有分別嘅，因為你講咗話誒喺將呢啲人即係犯規嘅人交畀警務人員拘押之前咧，呢啲獲授權人士係可以扣留佢嘅。
咁呢個程序就同我哋立法會誒差唔多啦，但係我哋立法會都要向公眾交代，即係我哋好多守則啊，各樣嘢都係寫得好清楚。我哋亦都唔會出胡椒噴霧啊，亦都唔會有警棍啊，各樣嘢係嘛？咁但係即係呢度，我覺得管理局你要同我哋解釋得翻好清楚。
The whole philosophy is that we avoid confrontation. We don't want to end up in a battle. That's not the purpose of a park or an open space. So the authorised people may be people we employ or people that we appoint. For example, as you said, security guards. We may have some. They will certainly not be.
try to deal with issues on a discussion basis. We're not trying to confront people and cause problems. However, if people are, for example, damaging property or causing problems for other other park users, you have to be able to step in and take action where it's appropriate. But at all
as they would for any public operation, so that the the public will know exactly what we mean, and those are things that we're working on at the moment. In terms of section seven that you particularly identified under 23 sub-section seven, require them to accompany the authorised person to.
或要 detain the person is basically to allow us to take a situation and remove the people that are causing the problem from that situation. But beyond that, we will have no power to take further action. So that's very clear and is will be set out in the guidelines that we'll be issuing separately.
嗱，主席，我我就要跟進嘅呢度。頭先Mr Prescott咧就話嗰個合理武力嗰度咧，佢哋係會誒有guideline啦，即係噉。我當然係希望即係管理局要將呢啲誒守則指引係公開畀我哋睇得到，佢係點樣去傳釋合理武。
冇力啦，即係否則我哋今日喺呢度過都係唔得嘅。誒，雖然頭先Mr.Prescott講明，佢一定唔會係即係有裝備，即係definitely not armed officer。噉就一定係即係我估你最多都係有對講機，最多都係整個即係CCTV cam即拍即錄，等你第日做證。
寫喺呢度呢套守則係能夠有效地執行，但係又唔會過分地。
嘅秩序維持嘅需要啊嘛，噉我想管理局話翻畀我哋聽，你喺召警求援。
或者勸喻到你決定要罰佢，即係決定要執法，你就有權問佢攞身份證，跟住抄低咗就。
點做嗰個大字嘅手續點咧？好嘛？係咯，即係你喺邊喺邊一點，你會揾警察入嚟就交畀警察去處理。咁呢啲我哋都想即係喺邊個程度，你會咁做？下次報告翻咧。OK。
What I suggest is, we'll give you the information, the training requirements for our park ambassadors and that sort of thing. So we'll provide that to members at the next meeting. I can say very briefly, they're they're
好，陳志全。係誒，其實我都係問執法嘅問題，但係我就係針對翻條例裏邊寫咗嘅第三部公眾行為。公眾行為裏邊咧，十三括弧一就有A至M咁多樣寫得好清楚嘅誒。
唔容許嘅行為，如果觸犯咗咧，就可以處第一級嘅罰款嘅。我就想問嗰個執法過程係點？譬如大小便、吐痰、行乞，啊，咁呢啲你係個係咪個park ambassador見到佢？
證據啊，呢啲噉嘅嘢，即係呢啲唔係攻擊性嘅嘅嘅裝備，即係最多就係噉樣樣。咁而家就有個有一類人啦。頭先啊，Mr.Prescott講咗就叫做Park Ambassador。噉我我都唔知中文係乜嘢。咁可唔可以管理局向我哋提供翻資料？而家即係已經。
經有嘅呢一類誒執勤嘅人員，誒叫做park ambassador嘅人，佢哋究竟係誒誒嗰個入職嘅條件係乜嘢？佢哋嗰個工作性質而家係點樣？噉我哋有個底知道，即係你將來如果係靠誒呢一批park ambassador去誒。
very much about having a presence in the park. They're about being obvious so they can help people. We've used the word ambassador because we want that notion of people being able to interpret and inform, help them, guide them, tell them how if they want to find where the toilets are, where where to go.
There are a source of information. There are obviously eyes and ears in the park for us as well. Yes, we will have CCTV, but CCTV is not a very effective way to on the spot deal with issues. You need people on the spot, and that's where our park ambassadors come in. They will of course be supplemented by a certain small number of security guards, but I.
as we're already doing, the security guards generally are employed for events, so they help to control the event, not the park generally. So that we're making a distinction already between the sort of need for control and the need for information. But I will provide that information. 開後提供。啊，主席，咁個編制都重要嘅。其實我哋即係
誒誒，當初去去睇呢個誒管理局，佢誒做負例嘅時候咧，我哋調翻轉頭，亦都關心管理局有冇咁多嘅資源去請咁多人嚟維持秩序。呢個admin嘢嚟㗎喎。係啦，咁唔應該係法例嘢喎。啊，呢個唔係法例，不過我哋擔心佢點執行法例啫。我諗起西九小組嗰度，你提出啦。係啦，我哋都擔心佢點樣執行呢？
啊！我諗我列表都係咯，同埋主席，即係另外一樣咧，連編監你都要理埋，我諗咪理唔掂？唔係我我哋我哋唔會理佢呢啲，但係但係就呢個關乎法例係邊度咧？就如果佢哋人手好有限嘅時候咧，噉我哋想象之中，佢處理唔到一啲嚴重啲嘅，或者係有啲規模。
即係我我相信你一定有呢個需要嘅。即係如果喺喺嗰個地界上邊係出現罪案啊，或者其他你誒普通park ambassador處理唔到，甚至係你請嘅護衞公司都處理唔到嘅情況嘅時候，噉你某一個情況就要召警求援。即係好似我哋立法會呢度噉，即係我哋自己。
yes, I mean.
主席。
佢嘅聯絡就可以即係發法庭傳票，跟住就上庭就去罰錢，係咪噉樣去執行咧？啊，好，嗯。
to be very respectful, to be very recognising. They're trying to enjoy themselves as much as every other user of the park. So that's the philosophy.
唔接受，唔容許佢勸喻咗，佢都唔去改善，你都係要照警先至可以去執行呢一啲誒。
所以call in the police， but we don't want to get to that situation. If you've reached that situation, it's already escalated. So the philosophy is to try and de-escalate by approaching them in a positive way， and
我諗講得好清楚啦。佢哋會做先嘅，因為每個情況都唔同，每件case等到佢不可能處理嘅先會揾警察嘅啫。
Our experiences that that works, but in order for our staff and for members of the public to be aware of the situation that's not acceptable, we felt that it was important to list in the bylaws those issues that would be the subject of that sort of intervention. So, for example, annoying.
嘅保安都未必所有嘢都處理到㗎嘛，要揾警察幫手啊嘛。噉我就需要西九管理局話畀我哋聽，你嗰個街欄喺邊度啦，即係幾時係邀請警方入去啦？定抑或係其實你即係恆常已經有個機制同食環啊、警方啊嗰啲即係大家去溝通。於是乎你。
去幹預使用呢個公園嘅居民咯。咁呢啲你唔會喺個法例度寫到嘅，呢啲in-house rule佢哋自己寫㗎啦。係，我哋就係關心佢點樣執行到呢啲例咯。咁呢啲就留翻喺行政裏邊講咯。譬如話你，主席，嗰啲係講唔曬㗎喎，你係嘛？我又。喂，佢佢佢帶只龜嚟，然後只龜係稀有動物。唔係我我。噉你？
要咪要揾四環全執啊！我又唔贊成你嗰個approach，因為因為即係嗱，我哋睇呢啲法例睇呢啲守則，我哋都要諗下佢點樣執行㗎嘛。咁好啊，咁咪不如你大概下次叫住啊啊Mister Pascal咧，就話翻畀我哋聽，如果遇到佢哋唔係佢哋嘅範圍或者佢哋能力唔做唔到嘅時候，佢哋會。
the the list here is is intended for clarity so that people know what we regard as antisocial behaviour basically as far as the action again let me stress this is based on our existing practice in the nursery park we found that when we approach people to explain the situation to them
We very rarely get the problem. People do respond positively to that approach. So where we've had people, for example, smoking in the park, the park ambassadors will go up and say, look, sorry, there is a smoking area. Would you mind moving to the smoking area? And actually, they will. People are people are very good. I think this is this is the philosophy.
We want to trust people to be sensible in the situations. The problem is there comes an occasion where someone won't respond to that, and that's where you need to have the additional power of being able to, if necessary, request them to come with you to detain them. And as we'll describe at the next meeting, if necessary.
誒，何叔林。
Run recently, we've got events coming up.
因為而家調翻轉頭咧，要得你書面準許先正準，嗰度就係inexhaustive。
噉你可唔可以解翻即係畀我哋聽係係即係你嗰個範圍係點樣拉裂咧？OK。
And always, our primary concern is safety for all park users, not just the event attendees.
Mr. President, again, based on the experience we've already had running the park for eight months.
好過康文處，但係調翻轉頭咧，就係如果要做其他嘢咧，就要得到你書面準許。
如，比如，即係大家想象，你而家將女人街搬咗去西九，咁呢啲當唔當活動咧？嗰邊係啦，嗰邊就係打太極。
We assess them when people approach us for for information. We talk to them, we assess the event, and then we take a view. So far, it's worked very well. We've been able to accommodate a wide wide range of different types of event.
到一 person may not be annoying to another person. So how do you interpret it? And that's where the training for the for the the park ambassadors comes in. We want to train our people to have the right approach, so that from the very first time they go into the park, they know how to approach people, how to address them.
O.K.陳志柱主席，主席，我明白係個勸喻會行先，但係你寫咗喺嗰個附例嗰度咧，我就想你講翻你會點執啊？譬如大小便噉，嗱，而家香港都話成日有啲啲噉嘅中港矛盾。如果有有客見到有人嚇大咗便已經發生咗，跟住去投訴，跟住。
如果真係要你去執法，噉你會唔會去執法？你個執法係點樣？係要召警求助至可以執法啦，定係你可以抄低佢身份證就已經可以事後去告佢？我係想問翻個個程序嗰個可能性啫。We we can if necessary. Yes, the powers are provided for under the bylaws to allow us to do.
And obviously, if if it were a case that we had someone that was coming in and deliberately doing that, we would have to take action, perhaps even calling in the police to take action under the relevant general laws of Hong Kong. But you know, those situations. 馬先生係咪係咪係咪一定要照警先？譬如啲A至M呢啲，如果你真係覺得。
跟住先可以再令佢上庭啊，咁咧。No, we don't have to call in the police. We can take action. We can prosecute under these bylaws ourselves. We can issue those sort of that sort of action. So we don't have to call in the police. I'm talking about when it gets out of hand. Then we always have recourse to the police, just as anyone else would. What I'm describing is that we don't.
係啊，主席啊，嗱，確實咧就誒呢度呢套誒誒附例咧，比康文處嗰啲咧就好啲啦，即係又冇講到話唔準除除草地分啊，唔準唱歌啊，唔準跳舞啊嗰啲各樣嘢。咁但係咧，雖則你唔準嘅嘢咧就少。
咁咧，即係呢度呢度，其實我哋又唔知道你嗰個權力係有幾大喎。因為嗱，你即係譬如好似第十條噉，即係舉行活動噉。咁呢個舉行活動即係點解咧？因為一舉行活動就要得到你書面嘅準許啊嘛。嚇咁呢啲活動係大定係細嘅。
嘅活動咧，誒，比如下低你都有講話啊，就呢個嘅活動你要有支架啊、攤位啊、平台啊、展品，咁大家就會諗哦，呢啲係咪即係好似美酒佳餚節啊嗰啲噉樣樣，即係有埋火啊、煮食啊嗰啲，即係有特別嘅準許啦。但係一啲細型啲嘅活動，比如
誒當然有音樂㗎啦，並且好大聲嗰啲啦嚇。呢邊又法輪功練功，嗰邊咧就跳大媽舞咁嚇。咁呢啲活動，我哋常人理解都係活動嚟㗎嘛，係嘛？雖則佢未必需要話誒整支架攤位咁多，但係一定係有音響啊。噉你你呢啲係咪都要你書面準許？
然後先正可以做咧。咁究竟如果冇書面準許喺呢個公園裏邊可以做嘅嘢，其實係幾多咧？即係我擔心你雖則你唔係好似康文署噉話呢樣不準嗰樣不準，但反為康文署嗰啲由一數到二十嘅不準咧，我哋睇到有邊啲不準喎？因
繼續。
所以那係個approach。
十點九個字到，依仲有時間。
咁噉就請局方即係提供我哋頭先攞嗰啲資料啦。
噉啊，睇睇誒，大家擸低呢個時間係嘛？咁咧就係開會嘅。另外，我哋諮詢嘅時間係咪另外再定啊？
講嗰啲意見咧又有啲唔同，有啲出入嘅，噉我覺得我哋都要聽一次嘅。好，好，冇問題。咁咧，我哋如果能夠，誒，如果係能夠再擬定開會嘅時間咧，就係四月十八號，嚇上晝。
議咧，我哋喺主體法喺依唔係喺依個法例裏修訂法例裏邊誒討論嘅時候咧，都係講誒都會討論翻我哋好關注嗰啲可以比較詳細啲去去討論大家所關心嗰啲，好嘛？嗯。噉我哋暫時今日咧，如果冇其他特別嘅嘢，我哋依個議程就。
Ad hoc events, people turning up and playing guitar among themselves, not a problem. We would never have an issue with that. Events involving cooking, yes, we would we would require a permit for that because of the safety issues. So that's basically the distinction we make. But we've now run the park.
the nursery park for over eight months. We we have very clear guidelines on the usage of the park, which are again on our website if people want to know. For events, we've had everything from running and sports events through to clock and flap, through to free space happening every other week, to small events. We've had the Doraemon.
Protection of the park because of course it is natural environment. You need to be able to make sure that it isn't overused. So you don't want too many events back to back. So we need to control it for that purpose. And also you may have two or three events happening at once. So you need to make sure that they are in appropriate locations. So these are the considerations.
That we apply, but honestly, it's a dynamic situation. It's a managed situation to allow as much flexibility as possible, which is why we have not prescribed. And I think it would be wrong if we were to take that approach of LCSD, which is fine for that sort of operation, but we want to be different. And the approach that we've taken, based on our
own experience of not prescribing in a whole list what's possible, what's not possible, allows us much more flexibility and freedom. And if people have have come to us with a proposal and we discuss it, and we usually have been able to resolve dates, times, etc. to suit both ourselves, the other park users and the prospective
啊！主席，我就好同意頭先啊，梁家傑議員咧提出嚟喺翻主體法例嗰度咧，即係個有個mission statement嗰度嚇。噉我就好同意佢個講法嘅。其實我哋而家制定呢套附例咧，最好咧就係喺即係一開宗明義嗰度咧，就講明呢套附例嘅制定。
同埋執行都要符合翻主體法例裏邊西九管理局嗰個嘅mission statement。咁咧就於是乎，大家喺詮釋，即係將來或者你有什麼嘅司法行動啊，或者係或者其他爭拗嘅時候啦，喺詮釋呢組法例嘅時候咧，就已經開宗明義喺埋呢個法例裏。
即係大家睇得到，哦，你係要符合西九管理局一成立開始嘅時候嗰一套嘅職能同埋個願景，噉我希望政府係可以做呢個修訂咯。有個有個依據。係啊，我諗咧，大家都提咗好好嘅意見，但係跟住下次會議，下次嘅會。
我哋就同埋嗰日就聽埋意公眾意見先，知啊，逐條審議，好冇？好。如果誒大家都同意咧，噉我哋就誒暫定四月十八號再開會。咁誒，如果冇其他事項咧，噉我哋今日嘅會議結束。多謝各位出席，thank you。
O.K.噉我哋想係而家繼續審議嗰啲法例咧，因為下次先審啦。不過我見人太少，都要下次先㗎啦，係嘛？係嘛？雖然我哋係早咗收工嘅，咁但係喺誒收工之前咧，我哋都仲有一個其他事項咧，就係想話大家覺得需唔需要我哋要有一個誒諮詢？
誒公眾嘅諮詢咧，誒聽下其他人對個扶禮或者使用一個公園嗰個意見。如果需要嘅時候，我哋就安排。要啊，主席要啊嚇。要啊，好嘅。即係雖則我理解管理局都應該諮詢咗好多㗎啦，咁但係即係好多時咧就誒誒官方機構嘅諮詢，唔知點解嚟到立法會呢度咧，市民嚟。
或者我哋夾埋啊，好嘛？因為而家你知都好逼巴啦。少人，我哋繼續做埋逐條審議啊。噉係咯，有個少人，我哋就即跟住就逐條審議啦，好嘛？或者我哋都定一個時間，或者係佢睇都唔會，我相信都唔會突然間多咗幾十人咁去嘅嚇。有需要嘅時候，我哋再加時啦。如果唔係，